

MAHMUD SHAMSUDEEN SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT ME

+2348106029359

Zaria, Kaduna State, Nigeria.

mahmudshamsudeen@gmail.com

https://somboy015c.github.io

LANGUAGES

YORUBA HAUSA

HOBBIES

- CODING
- FOOTBALL
- MOVIES

PROFILE SUMMARY

Mahmud Shamsudeen is the co-founder and CTO of Bookafrica, He is from kano State, Nigeria. He is a SSCE, Dip. Computer Engineering Certificate holder, currently an undergraduate student studying Computer Engineering at Ahmadu Bello University Zaria. He is passionate about Information Technology, sustainability, and community development with 5 years experience building different software, UI designs and hardware embedded systems for organizations, institutions, final year projects, and community development projects.

EDUCATION

Ahmadu Bello University, Zaria, Kaduna State. B.Eng. Computer System Engineering	2019 till date
Ahmadu Bello University, Zaria, Kaduna State. Dip. Computer System Engineering	2016 - 2018
Federal Government College Kano, Kano State. West Africa Secondary School Certificates (SSCE)	2009 - 2015

EXPERIENCE

Cofounder, and CTO

Bookafrica | 2023

I collaborated with creative minds from diverse field of expertise to build an idea into a real and sustainable business, where I have been required to take charge of the product design, development, and maintenance. – https://bookafrica.org

Web Developer

Martin and Monica Foundation | 2023

I was recommended to the foundation for the purpose of developing the organization's website, of which I was given the opportunity to work with the organization's Co-founders and some other team members of the organizations to deploy the software on the 31st of May 2023 as planned.

Web Developer & Graphics Designer

Alzillah Foundation | 2021 - till date

I had the opportunity to work with this organization base on my volunteer experience from a non-governmental organization I happened to work with, where I was given the task to design, develop, and manage the organization's website alongside creating media contents for its publicity. - https://alzillah foundation.org

Web Developer & Graphics Designer

PUP Industries | 2020 – till date

I worked with the management team of PUP Industries (The 2021/22 Enactus Nigeria National Competition winner) for a duration of 12 months, where I was given a task to design, and develop the company's ecommerce website for ease of reach for their customers. – https://pupindustries.com

General Secretary & Software development Lead

Enactus Ahmadu Bello University Zaria | 2021 – 2022

In the year 2021 I was nominated to the post for the 2021/2022 session. Alongside my other executives, we lead a team of 185 to the Enactus National Competition in Lagos that year, where we emerged the winners and represented Nigeria at San Juan Puerto Rico. As part of my goal as the general secretary was to digitalize the team and empower my team members with tech skills of which I successfully achieved and I and my development team developed the team's website, and created an automated team profiles for our members. — https://enactusabu.org.ng

UI/UX Designer

Respirare | 2023

I happened to join the Google Solution Challenge where I worked with three other team mates to develop a solution to health issues facing the communities. I was given the task of creating the User story and designing the interface for the developers to develop.

SKILLS

CODING:

- HTML / CSS
- JavaScript/jQuery
- PHP / MYSQL
- Python

DESIGN

- UI/UX Design
- Graphics Design
- PowerPoint Design
- Mockup Design

KNOWLEDGE

- Programming (Python, & C#)
- Photoshop Design
- Flutter Development
- Visual Studio C# App Dev.
- Figma Design
- Microsoft Office
- Embedded Systems Designs
- Arduino Development
- VS Code
- AI / ML

REFERENCES

Available upon request

UI/UX Designer

FarmerTech | 2022

I designed UI/UX that aided the presentation of the 2021 British American Tobacco's Battle of Minds Competition Regional winner's business idea for a duration of 6 months, intensively working with my team

OTHER PROFFESSIONAL TRAININGS

- Enactus Leadership Training | Covenant University, Ota. 2020 &2021.
- Student Working Experience Program | ABU Zaria, Kaduna State. 2020.
- Design Thinking by Intuit. 2022.

COMMUNITY AND VOLUNTEER WORK

- PUP Club (effect of plastic waste) for secondary school students. 2022.
- Cleanup Campaign in Samaru Community Zaria, Kaduna State. 2021&2022.
- Design and Installation of Plastic Collection centers in ABU Campus. 2022.
- Food Support Program in Zaria, Kaduna State 2021 & 2022
- Graphics Design Volunteer at Alzillah Foundation 2022
- Volunteer Member at Enactus Ahmadu Bello University 2020

CERTIFICATES AND AWARDS

- House Captain Of the Year. | FGC Kano 2015.
- 1st Runner Up ABU DEVS Hackathon. | ABU Zaria 2019.
- Certificate of Induction Enactus ABU. | ABU Zaria 2020.
- Battle Of Minds 3.0 Regional Champion | BAT West Central Africa 2021
- Certificate of Honor, Enactus ABU. | ABU Zaria 2022
- Delegate for the Enactus Leadership Conference | Enactus ABU. 2022
- Enactus National Champion 2022
- Action With Africa Award 2022
- Introduction to python, Intermediate Python, Data Manipulation with Pandas
 - Statement of accomplishment | Datacamp 2023

PERSONAL PROFILE

- Ability to work under minimum supervision
- Ability to quickly adapt, learn, unlearn, and relearn
- Ability to deal with confidential and sensitive information
- Self-motivated, disciplined, and target oriented
- Good interpersonal relationship & team work.